Guide to the New York State College of Home Economics records, 1875-1979
College of Home Economics records, 1875-1979
- Series XII. Printed Material
  - 4-H Club Members' and Club Leaders' Guides
    - Color and Room Arrangement-Leader's Guide, no date (Box 109)
    - Lighting, Lamps, and Lampshades-Leader's and Member's Guides, no date (Box 109)
    - Build it Yourself-Leader's and Member's Guides, no date (Box 109)
    - More Fun Caring for a Young Child-Leader's and Member's Guides, no date (Box 109)
  - Miscellaneous Bulletins
    - Farmhouse Planning in New York State, February 1951 (Box 104)
    - A Central Camp Building, March 1953 (Box 99)
    - Housing for Migrant Workers, June 1953 (Box 104)
    - An Expansible House, February 1955 (Box 104)
    - Making Shirts for the Men of the Family, April 1957 (Box 99)
    - A Farmhouse for Comfortable Living, May 1957-Reprint (Box 104)
    - Farm House Business Centers, March 1960 (Box 99)
    - Wooden Toys you can Make at Home, May 1961-Reprint (Box 99)
    - Home Activity Centers, December 1961-Reprint (Box 99)
    - Soups and Main Dishes, December 1961-Reprint (Box 99)
    - Homemaking Work Units, March 1962-Reprint (Box 99)
    - Community Meal Management, June 1962 (Box 99)
    - Hooked Rugs, June 1962 (Box 99)
    - Make Your Own Chair Covers, October 1962 (Box 99)
    - Your Automatic Dryer, September 1963 (Box 99)
    - Your Automatic Dishwasher, September 1963 (Box 99)
    - Your Household Range, September 1963 (Box 99)
    - How to Make Fabric Lampshades, September 1963-Revised (Box 99)
    - Making Shirts for the Men of the Family, February 1964-Reprint (Box 99)
    - Reupholstering Chairs With Foam Rubber, December 1964 (Box 99)
    - Furniture Restoration, June 1965 (Box 99)
    - Your Automatic Freezer, September 1967 (Box 99)
    - How to Make Curtains and Draperies, November 1967-Reprint (Box 99)
    - Sewing Made Easy, April 1968 (Box 99)
    - Food Makes a Difference, July 1968 (Box 107)
    - Cooking for One, September 1968 (Box 109)
    - Food-What For?, December 1968 (Box 99)
    - Make Your Own Chair Covers, July 1969-Revised (Box 99)
    - The Vacation Home Market, September 1969 (Box 99)
    - Be a Better Shopper, May 1970-Reprint (Box 99)
    - Furniture Restoration, June 1970-Revised (Box 99)
    - Food Makes a Difference, June 1971-Revised (Box 109)
    - Buying Clothes for Small Children, March 1974-Reprint (Box 99)
    - Cooking for One, December 1974-Reprint (Box 99)
    - Food Makes a Difference, April 1975 (Box 99)
    - 4-H Vegetable Crops: Making the Most of Your Garden, June 1974 (Box 107)
    - 4-H Vegetable Crops: Harvesting, January 1972 (Box 107)
    - 4-H Vegetable Crops-Selecting & Preparing Vegetables for Exhibition, June 1974 (Box 107)
    - Exhibiting Vegetable Crops, May 1966 (Box 107)
    - Factors Influencing Seed Germination, July 1978 (Box 107)
    - Safe Food Preparation: It's in Your Hands, March 1984 (Box 107)
  - Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletins (Box 99)
    - The Interior Quality of Market Eggs, 1914 (Box 67)
    - Two Factors Causing Variation in the Weight of Print Butter, February 1915 (Box 67)
    - Sizes of Purchasing Centers of New York Farm Families, November 1928
    - Organization of the Sewing Center in the Home, August 1929 (Box 99)
    - An Economic Study of Food Consumed by Farm and Village Families in Central New York, April 1930 (Box 99)
    - The Family Finances of 195 Farm Families in Tompkins County, New York, 1927-1928, May 1931 (Box 99)
    - Buying for the Household as Practiced by 368 Farm Families in New York, 1928-1929, June 1933 (Box 99)
    - A Study of the Food Habits and Health of Farm Families in Tompkins County, New York, June 1933 (Box 99)
    - A Study of Practices in Feeding Infants, June 1934 (Box 99)
    - Clothing Purchased by Farm Families in Tompkins County, New York, 1927-1928, June 1934 (Box 99)
    - The Control of Aphids on House Plants, January 1935-Revised (Box 99)
    - Ornamental Trees for New York State: Their Landscape Value and Care, January 1935-Reprint (Box 99)
    - History, Culture, and Varieties of Summer-Flowering Phloxes, February 1935-Revised (Box 99)
    - Pools for Home Grounds, June 1935-Revised (Box 99)
    - The Bearded Iris, July 1935 (Box 99)
    - Ten-Year Report of Studies in Child Development and Parent Education, October 1935 (Box 99)
    - Garden Roses, February 1936 (Box 99)
    - A Study of Price Differences in Retail Grocery Stores in New York State, February 1937 (Box 99)
    - The Planting and Care of Shrubs and Trees, July 1937-Reprint (Box 99)
    - The Culinary Quality of Apples as Determined by the Use of New York State Varieties, May 1939 (Box 99)
    - Some Comparisons Between Analyses and Film Records of Behavior and Guidance of Children, June 1939 (Box 99)
    - The Morphology of the Apple and Other Pome Fruits, April 1940 (Box 99)
    - The Rock Garden, May 1940-Reprint (Box 99)
    - Use of Time in Its Relation to Home Management, June 1940 (Box 99)
    - Installment Credit in the Sale of Washing Machines, November 1940 (Box 99)
    - Consumer Buying of Potatoes and Store Offerings, June 1941 (Box 99)
    - Relative Economy of Nutrients in Servings of Some Commonly Used Foods, December 1941 (Box 99)
    - Potatoes in Institution Food Service, June 1943 (Box 99)
    - Some Effects of the Height of Ironing Surface on the Worker, May 1946 (Box 99)
    - Personal and Family Values in the Choice of a Home, November 1947 (Box 99)
    - Functional Kitchen Storage, June 1948 (Box 67)
    - Family Laundry Practices and Costs, August 1948 (Box 99)
    - Relative Cost of Nutrients in a Serving of Food, October 1948 (Box 99)
    - Cake Quality and Batter Structure, August 1950 (Box 99)
    - Housing Preferences of Farm Families in the Northeast, July 1951 (Box 99)
    - Oxygen Consumed in Household Tasks, August 1951 (Box 99)
    - Housing and Journey to Work, August 1951 (Box 99)
    - Guides for Arrangement of Urban Family Kitchens, October 1951 (Box 99)
    - Rural Housing in New York State, October 1952 (Box 99)
    - Clothing Inventories of Outerware-103 New York Farm Families, June 1953 (Box 99)
    - Psychological Effects of Clothing-part II, July 1953 (Box 99)
    - Psychological Effects of Clothing-part III, July 1953 (Box 99)
    - Psychological Effects of Clothing-part IV, August 1953 (Box 99)
    - Social Change in a Central New York Rural Community, December 1954 (Box 99)
    - Fringe Families and their Social Participation, April 1955 (Box 99)
    - Adjustment to Retirement in Rual New York State, February 1956 (Box 99)
    - The Changing Farm Housing Inventory, July 1958 (Box 99)
    - Household Inventory and Use of Selected Milk FOrms in Two New York State Communities, December 1960 (Box 99)
    - Laundering, Dry Cleaning, and Abrasion STudies of Eight WInter Cottons and a Rayon-Acetate Fabric, December 1960 (Box 99)
    - Whiteness of Pillowcases Laundered in 206 New York State Homes, June 1961 (Box 99)
    - Work Before and After Addition of Functional Storage Devices in Home Kitchens, October 1961 (Box 99)
    - Trips Between Centers in Kitchens for 100 Meals, January 1962 (Box 99)
    - Consumer Satisfaction with Men's Shirts and with Women's Slips and Casual Street Dresses, July 1963 (Box 99)
    - The Elderly and Their Housing, December 1963 (Box 99)
    - Laundering, Drycleaning, and Abrasion Studies of Eleven Two-Fiber Mixed or Blended-Fiber Fabrics, December 1963 (Box 99)
    - Financial Management Practices of Families with Steady or Fluctuating Incomes, June 1964 (Box 99)
    - Your Road to Better Meetings, June 1964 (Box 67)
    - Consumer Satisfaction With Men's Shirts and With Women's Slips and Casual Street Dresses, December 1964 (Box 99)
    - Factos Related to Satisfaction with Girls' Blouses and Slips, May 1965 (Box 99)
    - Facts About Floor Care, July 1965 (Box 99)
    - Classification Systems: Household Expenditures Data and Household Accounts, July 1967 (Box 67)
    - Dishwashers-How to Choose-How to Use, December 1968 (Box 99)
    - Properties of Textile Upholstery Fabrics and Their Importance to Consumer Satisfaction, May 1973 (Box 67)
  - Information Bulletins (Box 99)
    - Physical Sciences Bulletin (DEA)-Understanding Automatic Dishwashers, October 1970
    - Physical Sciences Bulletin (DEA)-Phosphates and Detergents in Water Pollution, January 1971 (Box 99)
    - Physical Sciences Bulletin (DEA)-Knitted Apparel and Fabrics (Box 99)
    - Food Sciences Bulletin-Kitchen Tools and Pans, March 1971 (Box 109)
    - Social Sciences Bulletin (DEA)-Buy by Size, Not Age, September 1971 (Box 99)
    - Social Sciences Bulletin (Consumer Economics and Public Policy)-Shopping for Credit, May 1971 (Box 99)
    - Physical Sciences Bulletin (DEA)-Furniture and Window Fabrics (Box 99)
    - New York State College of Human Ecology: Information Bulletins, January 1972 (Box 107)
    - Plant Sciences Bulletin (Natural Resources) - Is Commercial Recreation Profitable?, May 1972 (Box 99)
    - Plant Sciences Bulletin (Natural Resources)-Selection and Care of Your Christmas Tree, October 1972 (Box 99)
    - Plant Sciences (Floriculture and Ornamental Horticulture)-Woody Plants Usefully Winter Hardy in the Coldest Regions of New York State-Reprint, April 1972 (Box 99)
    - Physical Sciences Bulletin (DEA)-The Laundry System: Fabric, Soil Supplies, January 1973 (Box 99)
    - Social Sciences Bulletin (Consumer Economics and Public Policy)-Who Decides? Participants in Community Decision Making, February 1973 (Box 99)
    - Social Sciences Bulletin-How are Community Decisions Made?, February 1973 (Box 99)
    - Social Sciences Bulletin-How Well Are We Represented?, February 1973 (Box 99)
    - Social Sciences Bulletin-The Dollar Value of Household Work, June 1973 (Box 99)
    - Plant Sciences (Floriculture and Ornamental Horticulture)-A List of Ornamental Plantsfor New York Seashores, August 1973 (Box 99)
    - Physical Sciences Bulletin (DEA)-Basics of Housecleaning and Home Care, February 1974 (Box 99)
    - Food Sciences Bulletin (Human Nutrition and Food)-Useful Facts About Baking, March 1975 (Box 99)
    - Food Sciences Bulletin (Human Nutrition and Food)-Kitchen Tools and Pans (Box 99)
    - Plant Sciences Bulletin (Floriculture and Ornamental Horticulture)-Christmas Decorations, July 1978 (Box 99)
    - Plant Sciences Bulletin (Floriculture and Ornamental Horticulture)-Growing African Violets, October 1978 (Box 99)
    - Citizen Advisory Committees: A Guide for Members and Potential Members, 1979 (Box 99)
    - Public Hearings: A Guide to Effective Participation, April 1980 (Box 99)
    - Plant Sciences Bulletin-The Selection, Care, and Use of Plants in the Home, March 1984 (Box 99)
    - Think Microwave, 1979 (Box 99)
    - Parliamentary Procedures, June 1984 (Box 99)
  - Research Publications (Box 99)
    - Cornell Recommendations for Trees and Shrubs-Revised, April 1962 (Box 99)
    - Cornell Recommendations for Trees and Shrubs-Commercial Production and Maintenance-Revised, April 1966 (Box 99)
    - Determinants of Family Saving, August 1970
    - Supplemental-Income Effects of Federal Food Programs for Selected Low-Income Households, 1972 (Box 99)
    - Ornamental Trees for New York States: Their Landscape Value and Care, 1934 (Box 104)
  - Cornell Rural Housing Leaflets
    - Color for the Home, May 1947 (Box 104)
    - Kitchens: Space Requirements for Equipment, Work Centers, and Cupboards, May 1947 (Box 104)
    - Sewage Disposal, November 1947 (Box 104)
    - Water Supply Systems, January 1948 (Box 104)
    - Farm House Plans, November 1948 (Box 104)
    - A Step-Saving U Kitchen-Leaflet #15, December 1948 (Box 104)
    - Easy to Build Kitchen Cabinets for the Remodeled Farmhouse, January 1949 (Box 104)
    - Cornell Kitchen Cupboards That Simplify Storage, June 1949 (Box 104)
    - Plan Price List, August 1957 (Box 104)
    - Cornell Housing Leaflet, January 1968-Revised (Box 104)
  - Home Economics Extension Leaflets
    - When You Buy Dining and Pull-up Chairs-#1, June 1967 (Box 107)
    - When You Buy a Lounge Chair-#2, November 1969 (Box 107)
    - When You Buy Wood Furniture-#3, April 1971 (Box 107)
    - Camp Food Services Records-#4, October 1967 (Box 107)
    - Pricing a Community Meal-#6, June 1963 (Box 107)
    - Textile Labeling-#7, April 1963 (Box 107)
    - Buying by Size Not Age-#8, September 1969 (Box 107)
    - When You Buy a Rug or Carpet-#9, December 1966 (Box 107)
    - Gravies and Sauces for your Community Meals-#12, November 1967 (Box 107)
    - Vegetables for your Community Meals-#13, January 1963 (Box 107)
    - Quantity Salad Preparation-#14, February 1967 (Box 107)
    - Quantity Coffee Preparation-#15, January 1963 (Box 107)
    - Painting Furniture-What to Paint-#16, May 1967 (Box 107)
    - Painting Furniture-How to Paint-#17, November 1971 (Box 107)
    - When You Buy Chair Cover and Upholstery Fabrics-#18, November 1965 (Box 107)
    - Keep the Quality in the Food You Buy-#19, August 1965-Reprint (Box 109)
    - Keep the Quality in the Food You Buy-#19, July 1967-Revised (Box 109)
    - Keep the Quality in the Food You Buy-#19, October 1969 (Box 107)
    - Finishing Wooden Salad Bowls, Spoons, and Forks-#20, December 1969 (Box 107)
    - A Financial Checkup on the Use of Credit-#21, January 1969 (Box 107)
    - When You Buy Curtain and Drapery Fabrics-#22, December 1966 (Box 107)
    - Modern Ways with Roast Turkey-#23, March 1966-Revised (Box 109)
    - Quantity Sandwich Preparation-#24, November 1965 (Box 107)
    - A Food Value Wheel-#25, December 1968 (Box 107)
    - A French Knife Speeds Food Preparation-#26, August 1963 (Box 107)
    - Making the Most of Household Storage Space-#27, November 1971 (Box 107)
    - Buy For Health-Milk and Cheese-#28, December 1963 (Box 107)
    - Buy for Health-Meat, Fish, Poultry, Eggs, Dry Beans and Peas, Peanut Butter-#29, December 1963 (Box 107)
    - Buy for Health-Fruits and Vegetables-#30, December 1963 (Box 107)
    - Buy for Health-Cread and Cereals-#31, December 1963 (Box 107)
    - Nutritional Facts about Fats-#32, January 1964 (Box 107)
    - Shopping for Shirts-#33, January 1968 (Box 107)
    - Men and Family Living-#34, April 1964 (Box 107)
    - Knitted Fabrics-#35, April 1965 (Box 107)
    - Construction Techniques for Knitted Fabrics-#36, April 1965 (Box 107)
    - Stretch in the Wardrobe-#37, February 1966 (Box 107)
    - Shopping for Credit-#38, December 1966 (Box 107)
    - Brighten the Family Wash-#39, January 1967 (Box 107)
    - The Voice of Clothing-#40, December 1969 (Box 107)
    - Calorie Sense and Nonsense-#41, February 1967 (Box 107)
    - Glazed Finish Over Enamel-#42, May 1972 (Box 107)
    - Interior Design-Furniture Selection-#43, May 1969 (Box 107)
    - Interior Design-Furniture Placement-#44, September 1969 (Box 107)
    - Accessories for the Home-#45, October 1970 (Box 107)
    - A Guide for CLothing Evaluation-#46, December 1971 (Box 107)
    - When is Food Safe? Guides for Your Decisions-#47, July 1969 (Box 107)
    - Seating and Chairs-#48, September 1969 (Box 107)
    - Let's Shop for Tablecloths and Place Mats-#49, May 1969 (Box 107)
    - Let's Shop for Towels-#50, February 1970 (Box 107)
    - Permanent Press! Durable Press! No Iron! What is It?-#51, May 1969 (Box 107)
    - Let's Shop for Blankets-#52, February 1970 (Box 107)
    - Let's Shop for Sheets and Pillowcases-#53, February 1970 (Box 107)
    - Textile Label Language, January 1974 (Box 107)
  - Consumer Education Leaflets
    - Cuts and Costs of Beef-#10, March 1968 (Box 107)
    - Selecting Beef by Quality and Use-#11, March 1968 (Box 107)
    - Your Choice of Cereal-#13, December 1967 (Box 107)
    - Potatoes-You Have a Choice-#14, December 1967 (Box 107)
    - Read the Label-#15, December 1967 (Box 107)
    - Food in the Light of the Law-#16, December 1967 (Box 107)
    - Shopper's Cent Saver-A Handy Guide to Help You Compare the Cost of Packages of Difference Sizes and Weights-#17, May 1968 (Box 107)
    - Shopper's Cent Saver-A Handy Guide to Help You Compare the Cost of Packages of Difference Sizes and Weights-#17, January 1971-Reprinted (Box 109)
    - Cut Food Costs When You Shop-#18, January 1972-Revised (Box 109)
  - Miscellaneous Publications
    - Our Job in a World at War, 1942 (Box 104)
    - Home Economics Newsletter: "The Echo", March 1966 (Folder 4, Box 107)
    - College of Home Economics, Cornell University: The Let's Eat Game, May 1967 (Box 107)
    - Cornell Home Economics Extension Bulletins, August 1969 (Box 107)
    - Publications from the New York State College of Human Ecology, November 1972 (Box 107)
    - Publications: New York State College of Human Ecology, September 1974 (Box 107)
    - Are You Weighing Your Future? Consider Natural Science and Home Economics, February 1963 (Box 107)
    - Figure Flattery-Miscellaneous Leaflet #85, September 1967 (Box 107)
    - Accent on You, The Modern Woman, September 1968 (Box 107)
    - Buying Beef for your Freezer, August 1968 (Box 107)
    - Food What for?, December 1968 (Box 107)
    - Clothes and the Woman, 1968 (Box 107)
    - Your Career as a 4-H Extension Agent-Home Economics in Cooperative Extension, 1968 (Box 107)
    - Make Your Kitchen Fit You, July 1969 (Box 107)
    - Dress in a Winning Way (Box 107)
    - Try This On for Size (Box 107)
    - Save Money on Meat-#1, Spring 1974 (Box 107)
    - Credit contracts: Read them careully-#2, Spring 1974 (Box 107)
    - Store Meat Carefully-#3, Spring 1974 (Box 107)
    - Credit: Understand it before you sign-#4, Spring 1974 (Box 107)
    - Children's Shoes: A buying guide-#5, Spring 1974 (Box 107)
    - Save on Food-#6, Spring 1974 (Box 107)
    - Young Children Learning, August 1970 (Box 107)
    - Laundering without Phosphates, March 1974 (Box 107)
    - Flammable Fabrics, 1972 (Box 107)
    - Permanent Care Labeling, 1971 (Box 107)
    - Be a Better Shopper (Box 107)
    - Controlling Your Weight-Ruth Klippstein (Box 109)
    - Diaper Debate (Box 107)
    - Pickles and Pickling (Box 107)
    - Nutrition-Pregnant Women, Young Children, Infants-Learning Packet (Box 109)
    - 4-H Clubs-Steuben County Brochure (Box 109)
  - Publications Reprinted from University of Minnesota
    - Easy Dishwashing-#1 (Box 107)
    - Rid Your Home of Rubbish-#2 (Box 107)
    - Cleaning...Sink, Tub, and Toilet-#3 (Box 107)
    - Dry Milk in Every Meal-#4 (Box 107)
    - Better Bedmaking-#5 (Box 107)
    - Broiling-#6 (Box 107)
    - Home Storage-#7 (Box 107)
    - Making White Bread-#8 (Box 107)
    - Daily Food Guide-#9 (Box 107)
    - Fruits and Vegetables-#10 (Box 107)
    - Breads and Cereals-#11 (Box 107)
    - Meat and Meat Foods-#12 (Box 107)
    - Hamburger-#13 (Box 107)
    - Milk-#14 (Box 107)
    - Should You Buy on Time?-#15 (Box 107)
    - Pots and Pans-#16 (Box 107)
    - Small Electrical Appliances-#17 (Box 107)
    - Cutting Up and Cooking a Chicken-#18 (Box 107)
    - Hair Care-#19 (Box 107)
    - Hair Styling-#20 (Box 107)
- Series XIII: Scrapbooks and Miscellany
  - Miscellany
    - Belgian broadside, 1923 (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - The Children's Charter (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Signed group photograph presented to Flora Rose, Berkeley, April 1944 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - Mounted photograph of unidentified woman (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - Two diplomas, rolled (Box 40)
      - Testimonial to Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose for Food Conservation (rolled). Genealogy information on the Van Rensselaer and Rose families, including photographs of Martha Van Rensselaer's grave. (Box 49)
    - Dean Canoyer's Desk Calendars, 1955-1962 (Box 50)
    - Calligraphic broadsides featuring quotes of Eleanor Roosevelt and Flora Rose concerning MVR and the study of home economics, c.1930-1965 (Box 58)
    - Photographs of Eleanor Roosevelt Memorial done in Mann Library, 1963 (Box 59, Folder 21)
    - Guide to the Archives of the College of Home Economics, compiled by Alice Stein, 1964 (Box 59, Folder 22)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1926, 1950s (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper article (encapsulated) from the New York Herald Tribune “A Triumph of Home Economics”, February 18, 1934 (Box 64)
    - Poster (encapsulated) Demonstration Train in Dryden at the Lehigh Valley Station, May 8, 1917 (Box 40)
    - Dinner plates used by Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose in their home; Bernice Hopkins received them from friends of Miss Rose. She in turn donated them to the archives (Box 91)
    - Silver Tea Sets and Trays from the College of Home Economics--Mu. #1116-1120 (Box 92-95)
    - Demitasse Cup and Sauce from the Green Room in the College--Mu. #1139 (Box 97)
    - Cup and Saucer used by Flora Rose and Martha Van Rensselaer (Box 105)
    - Postcards-Home Economics Building and Bailey Hall (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - The Domecon Baby in Verse (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Martha Van Rensselaer's society pins-includes a 1907 Cornell pin; 1920 Omicron Nu pin; 1925 pin; and New York State Mother's Assembly pin (Box 59)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Farm and Home Week Special, 1946 (Box 48)
    - Farmers' Wives Reading Course, 1902-1912 (Box 48)
    - Two Psalters; belonging to Martha Van Rensselaer (Box 48)
    - One large scrapbook of Home Economics (printed and typed material) (Box 48)
    - Two small scrapbooks of Martha Van Rensselaer-related clippings (Box 48)
    - Three large scrapbooks of Home Economics clippings (Box 48)
    - Scrapbooks Disassembled Scrapbook of "Let's Make a Dress" Radio Show - 3 folders (Box 48)
    - Scrapbook: The Cayuga Indian Feast (Box 49)
    - Scrapbook: Martha Van Rensselaer's Mother (Box 49)
    - Scrapbook: Wartime Conservation (Box 49)
    - Letter Book: Martha Van Rensselaer, 1901-1905 (Box 49)
    - Letter Book: Martha Van Rensselaer, 1902-1905 (Box 49)